### Contact

8335 Winnetka Ave #417 Winnetka, CA 91306 geneinjefferson@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/genein (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Classroom
Teaching
Elementary Education

### Languages

English (Native or Bilingual) Spanish (Limited Working)

### Certifications

Intercultural Competency Inventory
Executive Decision Making
Certification in Entrepreneurship
Developing Your Emotional
Intelligence

#### Honors-Awards

2016 Toastmaster Table Topics Champion

2015 Hart Vision Charter School Teacher of the Year

Innovation in Education Award

2013 PEOPLE Magazine Teacher of the Year Finalist

National Sontag Urban Educator Award

### **Publications**

Stephen Sondheim Inspirational Teacher Award Essay for Mr. Miller

American Teacher: Heroes in the Classroom

Debt to Destiny: Creating Financial Freedom from the Inside Out

'10 Extraordinary People – 10 Random Questions' Article

# Genein Letford, M.Ed

Intercultural Creativity ® Keynote Speaker, Best Selling Author, Create and Grow Podcast Host

**United States** 

## Summary

Intercultural Creativity® is now the top training need for this new era.

As an award winning educator, speaker and the 2019 LA LAKERS Business Women of the Year, my company, CAFFE Strategies, develops and facilitates intercultural creative thinking training (based on brain research) needed to inspire, revive and empower your employees to connect, create and innovate beyond cultural lines.

The critical need for intercultural creative thinking within ourselves and in our teams has now taken precedence over other workforce skills. Is your team ready to pivot, be agile and create solutions that your competitors can't yet see?

If not. Don't worry, we can help. We bring in unique strategies inspired from the top research that produces results.

#### AS A TRAINER

We can teach your team how to reawaken their ability to imagine, to 'see' beyond the norm and connect patterns that produce new ideas. We train on intercultural development and offer the IDI assessment. They will combine unrelated concepts to form new viewpoints, enhance their perspective agility and strengthen their metaphorical analyses that will improve their creative idea output. We also help C-level management create a 'creative inclusive culture' that supports healthy experimentation and courageous ideation.

AS A SPEAKER

Jazz and Similes: Language Meets Music

We have a team of keynote speakers that deliver engaging and relevant keynotes, talks and workshops (based on recent research) about the current need and implementation of creative thinking in business, bias training, intercultural mindsets and education. You can always expect up-to-the minute information, actionable next steps, tons of energy, a few laughs and incredible feedback.

#### SO WHY US?

If you're looking for unique, research based strategies to pull out the innovative ideas from your employees and conference attendees, then look no more. I have spent over 15 years working with creative geniuses and I am ready to bring the best techniques to you and your team.

We've worked and consulted with a variety of organizations including Kaiser Permanente, Woodbury University, Medtronics, Donorschoose, Superintendents National Forum and many other organizations and entrepreneurs needing to feel confident in their ability to create and produce effective ideas for a global workforce.

And...I know we can help you too! Shall we connect?

Genein Letford, M. Ed 2019 LA Laker's Business Women of the Year 2015 CA Charter Teacher of the year CAFFE Strategies, LLC

# Experience

CAFFE Strategies, LLC
Chief Executive Officer
January 2019 - Present (3 years 3 months)
Los Angeles Metropolitan Area

- -Founder and chief officer of a top 'intercultural creative thinking' professional development training organization
- -Developer and overseer of the unique Intercultural Creativity® curriculum development, programs and implementation
- -Lead over a team of creativity trainers, sales team and marketing specialists
- -Qualified administrator of the Intercultural Development Inventory Assessment on cultural mindsets
- -Home of the '7 Gems of Intercultural Creativity' and '16 Diamond Tools of Creative Thinking' Framework
- -Keynote speaker and company brand liaison;
- -Podcast host of CAFFE's Create and Grow Rich Podcast

Remarkable! A Speakers Bureau Virtual/In Person Keynote Speaker, Corporate Trainer February 2021 - Present (1 year 2 months)

Los Angeles Metropolitan Area

Keynote Speaker, Corporate Trainer

Signature Keynotes-

Intercultural CreativityTM:

Where Innovation Meets Inclusion

This new time calls for a new message. The value and success of our organizations lies within the creative potential of our employees. Genein's groundbreaking keynote inspires, informs and empowers your attendees to unleash their creativity while building a culture of inclusive innovation. Laugh, learn and leave with a fresh perspective for this new era.

Diversity Diamonds: Empowering Your Employees to Create with Passion and Purpose

2020 pushed conformity out the door. Celebrating the uniqueness of your employees is now your organization's superpower. Genein equips organizations with strategies to build creative cultures that highlight the diamond facets of team members for individual and corporate success. Your event will shine bright with Genein Letford!

Genein Letford Consulting Intercultural Creative Consultant, Best Selling Author, Keynote Speaker January 2012 - Present (10 years 3 months)
California

Creativity is now the most powerful element in business. Genein Letford knows this and has created programs, curriculum and transformational keynotes that reignite the creative force in business and schools. As a nationally awarded educator and a sought after international speaker, Genein has combined cutting edge research and her unique field experience to help her clients fully utilize their creative capacities.

Premiere Speakers Bureau Keynote Mainstage Speaker November 2019 - Present (2 years 5 months)

- -Engaging keynote presentations on the topics of creativity, innovative solutions and entrepreneurship
- -Dynamic one, two and three day workshops and seminars on developing creativity
- -Diamond of Destiny keynote on empowerment for young adults and women

Alumni360
Executive Director
January 2014 - Present (8 years 3 months)
Los Angeles, California

Alumni360 is a mentorship program that supports NACP alumni in the areas of scholarship acquisition, financial literacy, personal development and life skills. This multi-grade cohort meets once a month during the school year as well as throughout school vacations for social events, field trips, and the summer entrepreneurship camp.

DonorsChoose.org
Advisory Board Member, Asset Committee Member
January 2015 - October 2020 (5 years 10 months)
New York, NewYork

Honored to be a part of this dynamic non-profit supporting teachers, along with fellow board members, Jeff Weiner, Former CEO of LinkedIn, Richard Lovett, President of CAA, Stephen Colbert and more! Donorschoose.org is an online charity that makes it easy for anyone to help teachers access the resources they need for their classrooms. This is an amazing charity and I am proud to be the first educator on the board in the organization's 20 year history!

California State University, Northridge

Creativity Integration Lecturer, Masters Program January 2015 - November 2019 (4 years 11 months) Northridge

- Lecturer in the Micheal D. Eisner College of Education Master's program for the Seminar in Interdisciplinary Arts Education.
- Taught arts and creativity integration for educators receiving a master's degree
- -Developed engaging curriculum that incorporated creative thinking techniques

NEW Academy Canoga Park Creative Arts Integration Specialist, Educator, Community Liaison June 2005 - June 2019 (14 years 1 month)

Arts Educator, Gifted Coordinator, Media Specialist, Community Partnership Liaison

University of California, Los Angeles Program Coordinator, Office Director September 2000 - June 2002 (1 year 10 months) Los Angeles

Began as a volunteer, which soon followed with a promotion to Program Coordinator based on excellent performance and reliable commitment.

Interviewed and trained 30 volunteers to tour elementary/middle school students around UCLA.

Served as liaison between Recruiting Office and school administration, which included contacting, scheduling and confirming tour reservations.

### Education

Canoga Park

#### **UCLA**

Bachelor of Arts (BA), Psychology · (1997 - 2002)

California State University-Northridge

Master of Arts (MA), Curriculum and Instruction · (2006 - 2010)

Light University

Financial Coaching, Personal Finance · (2012 - 2013)

# Small Business Development Center

Certificate in Entrepreneurship , Business · (2015 - 2015)